Tehran, Iran

github.com/hasssanitman

linkedin.com/in/hasssanitman

Hassan Mohammadian

Software Engineer and Back End Developer

+98 911 378 8870

hassanitman@gmail.com

https://hasssanitman.ir

SUMMARY

Software Engineer and Back-end Developer with more than 6 years of experience, (re)designed and implemented small to medium software systems with teammates from 5 to 10 people. Development experience with Go, PHP, and JavaScript languages and work with SQL databases. Ability to configure different types of Linux services. Likes deep work, learning, and creating new things, and enjoys dealing with complex technical issues and finding solutions.

EXPERIENCES

Modaber System-e Shargh - Tehran, Iran Remote - Full-time

Golang Developer, Mid-Level

Apr 2023 - Mar 2024 (11 mos)

Some of the most important Accomplishments:

- Developed testable and scalable code using the repository pattern
- · Implemented efficient notification system using goroutines
- Used Redis as key-value caching

Datam Fanavari-e Kharazmi-e Arian (iBrand) - Gorgan, Iran on-site - Full-time

https://ibrandagency.ir

Jul 2020 - Feb 2023 (2 yrs 8 mos)

Patam Fanavari-e Kharazm
Full Stack Developer, Senior

Some of the most important Accomplishments:

- Managed 3 projects in a technical team with 5 members.
- Improved teamwork using Trello, and decreased bugs in the product up to 20% using the GitHub code review feature.
- Coached 4 interns to learn programming and find the right path.
- Designed 2 projects' Databases and increased the speed of queries up to 10 times by defining indexes.
- Redesigned the Yargar project to support the processes of other units affiliated and increase scalability.
- Built cross-sell and shopping cart reservation modules and resulted in 10% sales increase for 20+ businesses.
- Reduced support calls by 60% by adding the instant postal tracking code issuance module.

Projects' links: Carbon iBolak Automation

Freelancer - Gorgan, Iran Remote - Full-time

https://hasssanitman.ir

Full Stack Developer, Mid-Level

Apr 2018 - Jun 2020 (2 yrs 3 mos)

Responsibilities:

• Design, development, and implementation of a software solution to distribute agricultural inputs in Golestan province and prevent smuggling called Yargar.

Accomplishments:

- Reached an optimal and efficient solution by participating in 6 meetings with the related organizations' managers and reviewing the needs.
- Engineered the distribution process between 8 organizations, and provided a software solution.
- Organized and trained 27+ training sessions for the Yargar users.
- Provided a solution, which resulted in an 85% reduction in smuggling.
- 95% satisfaction of the Yargar users for excellent performance and high speed of doing things.
- Created electronic correspondence and introduction letters, reducing fuel and paper consumption by 60%.

Projects' links: Yargar Ojrat

Smart Makers of Verkan Technology - Gorgan, Iran On-site - Full-time

https://www.varkangroup.ir

Mar 2016 - Mar 2018 (2 yrs 1 mo)

Web Developer, Junior Accomplishments:

• Shaped Roundcube more user-friendly with CSS and increased the company's product sales by 5%.

- Launched more than 10 WordPress websites.
- Advised the CRM development team and assisted in parts of the project development.

EDUCATION

University of Applied Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

Oct 2013 - Oct 2015

Technical and Vocational University

Associate's degree, Computer Software Engineering Jan 2011 - Sep 2013

SKILLS